

#### SOLUTIONS ARCHITECT

Cape Town, South Africa

© (+27) 84 042 8715 | ■ deankayton@gmail.com | © dnk8n | ♦ dnk8n | 🖹 dean-kayton | 🛅 dnk8n

### **Summary**

A versatile tech enthusiast with hands on experience in back-end development, QA, Automation, DevOps and Cloud Deployments. Has interfaced with a variety of fields such as Transportation Engineering, Unified Communications, Web Analytics and Bioinformatics.

Possesses a broad knowledge of current technologies but aims to specialize in the fields of Reinforcement Learning.

Firm believer in infrastructure as code and frequently utilizes well adopted mechanisms to ensure that code is easily accessible and deploy-able in production.

## **Languages and Technologies**

**DevOps / QA** Ansible, Docker, Singularity, Vagrant, Packer, Terraform, AWS-CLI, Jenkins, Gitlab CI, JMeter

**Services** Elasticsearch, Logstash, Kibana, Apache Storm, OpenVPN

AWS Kinesis, EC2, ECS, Fargate, S3, RDS,

Frameworks Django, Hugo

**Programming** Python, Bash, PowerShell, Julia, MATLAB, Octave

**Libraries** Numpy, Pandas, SciKit-Learn, MatPlotLib, PyTest, DocOpt

Languages English

# **Experience**

#### HIV Diversity group, Division of Medical Virology, Department of Pathology

University of Cape Town, South
Africa

Oct. 2018 - Dec. 2019

BIOINFORMATICIAN

- Maintained Django based system used to manage HIV blood sample storage and related information
- Wrote a pipeline in Julia and Python for processing DNA sequence information
- Performed Machine Learning research proposal feasibility study in which funding was granted
- Designed and implemented a Django based sequence database which allowed traditionally file backed sequences to be extended with metadata and filtered

OpenDNA Cape Town, South Africa

BACKEND ENGINEER

• Drove adoption of DevOps culture amongst team, making ops tasks a shared and automated process where applicable

- Produced centralized logging system where logs were sent to Elasticsearch via Kinesis, eliminating performance problems at peak traffic
- Tuned Apache Storm to perform at a desirable throughput, with back-pressure properly configured at peak traffic
- Containerized services using Docker to simplify configuration and allow developers to replicate production environment closely
- · Developed automated Jira issue handling, aiding QA and management to track relevant stories and their deployment status

**VOSS**Cape Town, South Africa

SOFTWARE QUALITY ASSURANCE ENGINEER

Jul. 2015 - May. 2017

Aug. 2014 - Jul. 2015

May. 2017 - Oct. 2018

- · Managed automated test coverage and CI/CD, extending Python based framework with functionality as required
- Drove team discipline to follow best practice git strategies and treatment of virtual machines as ephemeral, eliminating unreproducible changes
- Mentored intern with little technical background, who secured permanent position in QA (remained in position for over 2 years)
- · Solved compatibility issues of GNU/Linux users using Webex to connect to meetings, by building and hosting a Docker container
- · Introduced staging environments which enabled developers to contribute to automated tests, distributing QA responsibility amongst team
- · Gained technical knowledge of the Microsoft Skype for Business and Exchange products, often approached for insight

Trafficon Cape Town, South Africa

Transport Engineer

• Produced road traffic micro-simulation models and presentations that demonstrated traffic problems and their solutions

· Learned Python to build bespoke logic into model, allowing simulation of minibus departure and indoor multi-story parking systems

#### Other Interests

# Reinforcement Learning: An Introduction, second edition(2018) by Richard S. Sutton and Andrew G. Barto

Worldwide, Online

Participant PRESENT

Flash / Rehive Hackathon Cape Town

Participant

 $\bullet \ \ \, \text{Extended previous transport based hackathon idea\ to integrated\ with\ a\ payment\ API\ to\ register\ journey\ intent\ even\ in\ remote\ areas$ 

#### **OpenAl Retro Gaming contest**

Worldwide, Online

Jul. 2018

Participant May. 2018 - Jun. 2018

- The aim of the contest was to train AI to succeed on unseen levels in Sega's Genesis/Megadrive Sonic series (in the hope that it would produce AI that generalizes well)
- I threw myself into the deep end (I was yet to cover some fundamentals in reinforcement learning), but simply familiarizing myself with some baseline algorithms and packaging it together with some Docker knowledge, I was placed 32 out of 229 on the leader board (Team: Broken-Robot)

#### **Lightning Talk, SPAN Digital**

Cape Town, South Africa

SPEAKER

Nov. 2017

• Getting DevOps tools to do the stuff Data Scientists don't want to. The presentation was on how to use tools like Packer, Docker and Vagrant to manage infrastructure as code (IaC)

#### #AccessCPT Transport Hackathon

Cape Town, South Africa

Participant Mar. 2017

 $\bullet \quad \text{Integrated with WhereIsMyTransport API to develop proof of concept for a futuristic public transport system with adaptive stops and line routing} \\$ 

#### **Certificates**

Jul. 2019 Machine Learning, Stanford Online

Coursera, Online

Nov. 2016 Machine Learning Foundations: A Case Study Approach, University of Washington

Coursera, Online

 $Aug.\ 2015\ \textbf{ 6.00.1x: Introduction to Computer Science and Programming Using Python}, \ \textbf{MIT} \textbf{X}$ 

edX, Online

### **Education**

#### **Durham University**

Durham, United Kingdom

MEng(Hons) Civil Engineering

Oct. 2008 - Jul. 2013

• Thesis: Genetic algorithms applied to the optimization of steel space-frame roof structures